<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/Gasifier-Production/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/Gasifier-Production/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-02-17T20:51:34+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Gasifier-Production/</id><title type="html">Gasifier production</title><subtitle>A site where you can contribute to our gasifier production videos</subtitle><author><name>Anthony Simm</name></author><entry><title type="html">TLUD Gasifiers</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Gasifier-Production/2018/02/15/TLUD-Gasifiers.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="TLUD Gasifiers" /><published>2018-02-15T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2018-02-15T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Gasifier-Production/2018/02/15/TLUD-Gasifiers</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Gasifier-Production/2018/02/15/TLUD-Gasifiers.html">&lt;p&gt;There are many different types of gasifiers. We are focussing on the TLUD type. It produces gas for cooking and charcoal. 
TLUD stands for top lit up-draft, and it basically just means that you set your fuel in the gasifier on fire at the top, all over the surface.
We mostly use wood chips for fuel (or biomass pellets), and after a couple of moments, the first black spots appear;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/image1.png&quot; alt=&quot;image1&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
every piece of fuel then ignites its’ neighbour below, and soon the surface is all black from the forming charcoal. 
So in the beginning, you just have one flame, above the fuel. But the zone between wood and charcoal (the black material above the wood chips), a flaming disk shaped area called pyrolysis zone, slowly travels downwards; 
&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/image2.png&quot; alt=&quot;image2&quot; /&gt;
in our case probably at a rate of 1 cm every 2 minutes. So after a moment, we have two flames; one above the charcoal and another one in the pyrolysis zone, where wood turns to charcoal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The air that keeps this conversion process alive enters the gasifier at the lower end, and travels through the fuel; then it reaches the pyrolysis zone. It is called primary air and its’ flow must be somewhat throttled so that the gas that rises from the pyrolysis zone contains CO (and other gases), but no oxygen (O2) and only a little CO2. Above the charcoal, there is ambient air, and the flame which has been burning since the beginning consumes the flammable gas mix (“wood gas”) that emerges from the charcoal. When all wood has turned to charcoal, the flame stops.
&lt;img src=&quot;../assets/images/image3.png&quot; alt=&quot;image3&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trucks and cars have been operated on wood gas, in areas and times of limited petroleum supply, but those gasifiers have a different design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All pictures above are screenshots from here: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=m2Cjt7AiZJY&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Anthony Simm</name></author><summary type="html">There are many different types of gasifiers. We are focussing on the TLUD type. It produces gas for cooking and charcoal. TLUD stands for top lit up-draft, and it basically just means that you set your fuel in the gasifier on fire at the top, all over the surface. We mostly use wood chips for fuel (or biomass pellets), and after a couple of moments, the first black spots appear; every piece of fuel then ignites its’ neighbour below, and soon the surface is all black from the forming charcoal. So in the beginning, you just have one flame, above the fuel. But the zone between wood and charcoal (the black material above the wood chips), a flaming disk shaped area called pyrolysis zone, slowly travels downwards; in our case probably at a rate of 1 cm every 2 minutes. So after a moment, we have two flames; one above the charcoal and another one in the pyrolysis zone, where wood turns to charcoal.</summary></entry></feed>